Why is it that the secrets don't cause
cardomigali if they both uh increase
IGF?
>> Good question. The answer is because
they are something that naturally occurs
within the body. So in other words, the
concept is that your body will never
self-destruct
when it's secretreting its own
substances. When the body does
self-destruct, we have a name for that.
It's called cancer, right? So in the
absence of cancer, your body only
produces what it can substantially
handle without
any negative side effects.
With that said, if you stay on a secret
for a long period of time, and as I said
earlier, even if you're deficient over
the course of time, you're still going
to have a larger heart than you had when
you were younger, just due to time, just
wear and tear. All right. It's one of
those muscles that will grow the more
you're alive and the more it beats and
the the more your blood pressure goes
up. Everyone develops hypertension with
age just due to vascular resistance. You
know, body systems start to deteriorate.
Kidneys start to deteriorate. The
efficacy of your heart starts to
deteriorate. the left ventricle lining
starts to thicken, which makes the lumen
or the cavity of the left ventricle
smaller, which means that the amount of
blood you're able to pump with each
pulse is lower and therefore you're
going to have more strain on your heart.
When your heart is strained, it works
harder. When a muscle works harder, it
grows.
>> So, you know, a heart failure, if you
live long enough, is inevitable. And now
when you're coupling that with higher
level of supraphysiological
hormones that help the muscle grow, it's
going to be exacerbated.
Secretogs do not allow your body to get
into a supraysiological
range because by definition
suprahysiological
means above the limits of your
physiological capabilities.
And a secret simply pushes you to your
physiological capability.
>> So I know it's a little complicated. I
hope that makes sense though.
>> It makes sense to me. Uh
you're a little more medically inclined
than most. [laughter]
>> Yeah.
Do the secrets keep on working even in
older men? Maybe when their pituitary
gland um isn't that um good anymore?
>> Good question.
keep working is subjective. It's not a
well- definfined term. The answer is
yes. Will they optimize?
Depends on how good the gland that is
being
uh provoked. Uh will they optimize in a
90-year-old the same way as they'll
optimize in a 40-year-old? Presumably
not,
>> right? Depends on the individual, but
presumably not. Will they push a
90-year-old past where he is currently?
Yes. Yeah. I mean, if you poke something
with a stick, it's going to respond more
than if you don't poke it. So,
>> provoking a gland to do something will
yield a response. How good is the
response is going to be dependent on
that individual at that point of time
and their health.
>> So, there's not a certain point of or
age that you should switch to GH because
the creatog don't work anymore. If you
switch to growth hormone, you're I feel
forget even from a liability litigation
standpoint, from a medical health
standpoint, I feel that the risk of
exogenous growth hormone outweighs the
benefit.